Rory Hartong-Redden

June 7, 2024 | Boulder, CO | roryhr@gmail.com | roryhr.com

Summary

Experienced data scientist and ML Engineer with eight years of experience in the data world. I'm primarily hands-on but I have two years of management experience leading a data science team.

Tools

Python, Julia, Elixir, SQL, Git, Bash AWS, Docker, CircleCI, CI/CD
SQL, Postgres, Spark, Hadoop, S3
Jupyter Notebooks, PyCharm

Python Tools: Flask, Pandas, scikit-learn, requests, pytest, PySpark, XGBoost, TensorFlow, Conda

Professional Experience

• SyBridge Technologies (formerly Fast Radius)

Boulder, CO

Technical Manager and Lead Data Scientist

Aug 2021-May 2024

- Leading the data science team as we expand and improve models that instantly quoting parts
- Maintained documented code with a solid test suite and automated Datadog tests for latency and uptime
- Trained a random forest regression model of cycle time for CNC costing
- Predicted shipping costs using mixed integer programming and the UPS API

• Fast Radius Chicago, IL

Data Scientist Feb 2020-Aug 2021

- Tech stack: Python, scikit-learn, Flask, Docker, AWS
- Developed and maintained machine learning models in production to instantly quote the FDM additive process

• runtastic Linz, Austria
Data Engineer Oct 2018–Sep 2019

- Tech stack: Python, Spark, Hadoop, Flume, Oozie, Hive, RabbitMQ
- Led the design and deployment of a "People You Might Know" data product using Spark, scikitlearn, SparkML, and Elasticsearch
- Built a data exchange prototype with Kafka and a production system with AWS S3

• Allstate

Research Analyst

Menlo Park, CA

Jul 2016–Sep 2018

- Tech stack: Python, Pandas, Tensorflow, Spark, Julia, PostGIS
- Trained machine learning models and analyzed telematics and crash data for risk prediction
- Co-authored a paper on our research "Real-time Prediction of Intermediate-Horizon Automotive Collision" with the Stanford Intelligent Systems Lab

Education

• University of California, Santa Barbara

Santa Barbara, CA

Dec 2014

MS Mechanical Engineering

- Thesis research: Incorporated an image processing technique for cheap 3D high speed mm-resolution measurement over a surface area of $225\,\mathrm{cm}^2$

• University of California, Santa Barbara

Santa Barbara, CA June 2010

BS Physics & BS Mechanical Engineering